BoroLine, Jaybirpara T.E, Birpara, Alipurduar, West Bengal, Pin: - 735204

□ (+91) 8145804812 | Sankhadeepdey99@gmail.com | 🖸 lamshankhadeep | 💆 lamshankhadeep

Summary _

In a Nutshell, I am a Full stack developer.

I have experience of 5+ years in full stack development. Connecting web app to the database and serving multiple users from a single web application always motivate me to keep learning more about this technology. So, learning at a daily basis is my habit.

The Tech I know Typescript, Javascript, express, node, mongodb, react, redux, html, css, react-native, remotion and learning postgres, redis, graphql.

Experience _____

Camcorder.Ai Birpara, India

FULL STACK DEVELOPER Aug. 2023 - Present

- Integrated Remotion player and Remotion lambda as their video pipeline.
- Added transcript editor and support for deleting and editing words in the transcript.
- Added support for multiple videos and transcript on a single remotion composition.
- Integrated S3 for storage related to image, video, audio and attachment upload, cloudfront as a content delivery network, deepgram for transcription generation, modal to process video on the fly, lambda for serverless compution.

Funnel Rolodex (a sister company of ClickFunnels)

Birpara, India

FULL STACK DEVELOPER May. 2021 - Present

- Integrated Stripe for end to end payment infrastructure, with webhook to support realtime update.
- Design and Implemented a Real Time messaging center for 50k users, using hasura and graphql subscription.
- Cut down our render time of service listing page from over 3sec to under 1sec.
- Integrated aws ebs for micro services, s3 for storage related to image and attachment upload, cognito for authentication, cloudwatch to collect monitoring and operational data, lambda for serverless compution.

Remotion Birpara, India

LEAD COLLABORATOR Feb. 2021 - Present

- Added support for "Custom puppeteer-core / Apple M1 support"
- · Added support for H265, VP8, VP9 codec and customized CRF for ffmpeg to render video in different video format.
- $\bullet \ \ \text{Working on `@remotion/player' by which we can play react component as a video in browser itself.}$

Technixia Automation Birpara, India

FULL STATCK DEVELOPER Nov. 2020 - Mar. 2021

- Working on a mobile app for the iot solution using react-native, redux and mqtt.
- Implemented mgtt server on backend and connected backend server to mongodb to store all the mgtt data.
- Created a dashboard web app using react, redux to control hardware using web and iot.

DelivastBirpara, India

FRONTEND DEVELOPER Apr. 2020 - Nov. 2020

- Developed delivast.co.za (Demo) website using react, styled-components, redux, rest api
- Added messaging service between user and operator
- Developed dashboard web app for delivast (Demo) using react, styled-components, redux, rest api
- Optimized react web app load time from 1.3 sec to 450ms.

Software Heritage Birpara, India

OPEN SOURCE CONTRIBUTOR

Jan. 2020 - Mar. 2020

- Implemented Web API like URL and URLSearchParams in frontend to avoid manual appending of string.
- Implemented a checkbox which was missing on some specific URL.
- To save some request to the backend, implemented an algorithm to check search query in the frontend.

Honors & Awards

Education

October 19, 2023 Shankhadeep Dey · Résumé

Siliguri Institute of Technology

Siliguri, India

B.Tech in Electronics and Comunication Engineering

July. 2016 - June. 2020

- CGPA 8.32
- Got Swami Vivekananda Scholarship from West Bengal govt which is given to meritorious and economically backward students of West Bengal student.